https://masoniccollection.co.uk/privacy-policy-terms-and-conditions

ORDER NOW 0800 270 7699 /
024 7644 3469 ALL MAJOR CREDIT CARDS ACCEPTED
Home
» Privacy Policy / Terms & ConditionsPrivacy Policy / Terms & Conditions
Tweets by masoniccollect
Privacy & Cookies Policy
1. Introduction
1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors and customers; in this policy we explain how we will handle your personal data.
1.2 By using our website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.
1.3 Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct marketing communications and limit the publication of your information. You can access the privacy controls within the customer account area of our website.
2. How we use your “personal data”
2.1 In this Section 2 we have set out:
(a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;
(b) in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data;
(c) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
(d) the legal bases of the processing.
2.2 We may process data about your use of our website and services ("usage data"). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.
2.3 We may process your account data ("account data"). The account data may include your name, email address, telephone number, fax number, newsletter subscription preference and postal address. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and/or the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.4 We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services ("publication data"). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and/or the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.5 We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services ("enquiry data"). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you.
2.6 We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website ("transaction data"). The transaction data may include your contact details, select payment details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely our interest in the proper administration of our website and business.
2.7 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters ("notification data"). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.8 We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us ("correspondence data"). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.
2.9 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.
2.10 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.
2.11 In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
3. Providing your personal data to others
3.1 We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.
3.2 We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
3.3 Financial transactions relating to our website and services may be handled by our payment services providers as listed within our checkout pages. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers' privacy policies and practices on their own company websites.
3.4 We may disclose your enquiry data to one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and services identified on our website for the purpose of enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party's use of your personal data.
3.5 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 3, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
4. International transfers of your personal data
4.1 In this Section 4, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
4.2 We and our other group companies have offices and facilities in the United Kingdom. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which can be obtained from the Information Commissioner's Office.
4.3 The hosting facilities for our website are situated in the United Kingdom. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission, a copy of which you can obtain from the Information Commissioner's Office.
4.4 You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.
5. Retaining and deleting personal data
5.1 This Section 5 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.
5.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.
5.3 We will retain your personal data for a minimum period of 30 days following its provision.
5.4 In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention based on its necessity for the proper administration of our website and business and/or the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
5.5 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 5, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
6. Amendments
6.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
6.2 You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.
6.3 We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or other means of communication.
7. Your rights
7.1 In this Section 7, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.
7.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:
(a) the right to access;
(b) the right to rectification;
(c) the right to erasure;
(d) the right to restrict processing;
(e) the right to object to processing;
(f) the right to data portability;
(g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
(h) the right to withdraw consent.
7.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can request a copy of the personal data we hold by contacting us. Please note that we may in return request copies of valid identification.
7.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.
7.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
7.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.
7.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
7.8 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.
7.9 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
7.10 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:
(a) consent; or
(b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,
and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
7.11 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.
7.12 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
7.13 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us, in addition to the other methods specified in this Section 7.
8. Third party websites
8.1 Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.
8.2 We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties.
9. Personal data of children
9.1 Our website and services are targeted at persons over the age of 16.
9.2 If we have reason to believe that we hold personal data of a person under that age in our databases, we will delete that personal data.
10. Updating information
10.1 Please let us know if the personal information that we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.
11. About cookies
11.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
11.2 Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
11.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
12. Cookies that we use
12.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:
(a) authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website.
(b) status - we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website.
(c) shopping cart - we use cookies to maintain the state of your shopping cart as you navigate our website.
(d) personalisation - we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalise our website for you.
(e) security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally.
(f) advertising - we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you.
(g) analysis - we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services.
(h) cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally.
13. Cookies used by our service providers
13.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.
13.2 We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
13.3 We may publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. We publish Google AdSense advertisements on our website. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. This behaviour tracking allows Google to tailor the advertisements that you see on other websites to reflect your interests. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.
14. Managing cookies
14.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:
(a) https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
(b) https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
(c) http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
(d) https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
(e) https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
(f) https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).
14.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.
14.3 If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.
15. Cookie preferences
15.1 You can manage your preferences relating to the use of cookies on our website by following the steps in section 14 most relevant to your web browser software.
15.2 Please note that if you block cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features on our website. This may also “break” certain elements of our website and prevent them from functioning correctly for you only.
16. Our details
16.1 This website is owned and operated by Masonic Collection Ltd.
16.2 Our principal place of business is at 18 Central Avenue, Coventry, CV2 4DP, United Kingdom.
16.3 You can contact us:
(a) by post, to the postal address given above;
(b) using our website contact form;
(c) by telephone, on the contact number published on our website from time to time; or
(d) by email, using the email address published on our website from time to time.
17. Representative within the European Union
17.1 You can contact our Representative within the European Union with respect to our obligations under data protection law using any of the contact methods listed in section 16.3.
18. Data protection officer
18.1 You can contact our Data Protection Officer with respect to our obligations under data protection law using any of the contact methods listed in section 16.3.
Terms & Conditions
These terms and conditions (“Online Store Terms”) apply to all transactions concluded with you, the customer, when you shop via the Masonic Collection Ltd website (“the Website”) and the online store. Please read them carefully before placing your order and print a copy for your future reference. By registering at the online store you accept and agree to be bound by the Online Store Terms and the terms and conditions of the Website which together shall constitute the entire agreement between you and Masonic Collection Ltd.
Masonic Collection Ltd reserves the right to alter these Online Store Terms from time to time.
References in this document to "the online store" refer to the Masonic Collection Ltd online store at http://www.masoniccollection.co.uk operated by Masonic Collection Ltd.
The Online Store Terms are subject to English Law and the exclusive jurisdiction of the English courts. If any Online Store Terms shall be deemed unlawful, void or for any reason unenforceable then that Online Store Term shall be severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of the remaining Online Store Terms.
Acceptance of orders
Masonic Collection Ltd are only able to take orders through the online store for delivery to the countries listed on the checkout pages. If the country that you require delivery to is not visible then Masonic Collection Ltd will not be able to process your order.
Masonic Collection Ltd validate your order and credit or debit card details you submit to us before your order can be accepted. Once that has been done, Masonic Collection Ltd will confirm that your order has been received by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you provide in your registration form. Our confirmation of your order brings into existence a legally binding agreement between us.
Masonic Collection Ltd accept all orders for products and services subject to availability and certain security checks.
Masonic Collection Ltd accept payment by most major credit and debit cards. Payment will be debited from your account before the dispatch of your purchase. All credit and debit card holders are subject to validation checks and authorisation by the card issuer and Masonic Collection Ltd.  Masonic Collection Ltd will not be liable for any delays to your order this may cause. If the issuer of your payment card refuses to authorise payment to us or you fail our security checks, Masonic Collection Ltd will not be liable for any delay or non-delivery.
Availability of Products
If online store products become temporarily unavailable, Masonic Collection Ltd shall hold your order until Masonic Collection Ltd has the product back in stock and will then mail the product to you in the usual way. In the event that an individual product becomes permanently unavailable then Masonic Collection Ltd will seek to offer you a suitable alternative or give you a full refund.
Colour reproduction
Masonic Collection Ltd has made every effort to reproduce colours in the online store as accurately as possible. However, different computers reproduce colours in slightly different ways, and so exact colour matches are not yet possible over the internet. This means that when you order products from the online store, colours may differ from what you see on the screen. If you are not satisfied with the colour of the product you have ordered, Masonic Collection Ltd operate a returns policy.
Products and Pricing
All product prices include Value Added Tax (“VAT”) where applicable. These may change in line with UK government, Customs and Excise, EU directives, and other legal interpretations issued by relevant authorities.
Import duties and local taxes are NOT included in the quoted price of goods being delivered to outside the EU. You will be responsible for the paying of any and all import duties and local taxes including any administration charges upon receipt.
Masonic Collection Ltd reserve the right to amend any prices without any prior notice and at any time and the right to add or withdraw any product at any time.
Guidance
To the extent that Masonic Collection Ltd are permitted by law to limit our liability to you in connection with any order, that liability will not exceed the total price charged for the relevant product(s).
Your account
If you use the website, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password. You agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password.
Communication
You consent to receive communications from us electronically. You will always have the option to opt-out of future email communications.  This does not affect your statutory rights.
Offers / Vouchers
Any voucher or promotion displayed on the website or offered by us entitles you, at the time of ordering, to a saving on a new order placed with the Company. Details of the minimum spend, including VAT and saving entitlement can be found in your voucher email or promotion information.  The Company reserves the right to refuse redemption of vouchers that have not been issued by an authorised agent of the Company. Vouchers have a cash value of £0.001 and are not transferable or assignable. Only one voucher can be used per order and cannot be used with any other promotion. Vouchers and promotions are redeemable only against the value of goods purchased. They may not be redeemed against pack promotional offers, gift cards or additional services such as delivery charges or gift wrapping. In the event of returns, refunds will be given for cash as used in the original purchase above the value of the voucher or promotion.  In the event of part of the order being returned, the value of the voucher or promotion will be deemed to be spread between the goods proportionately. The sum in cash exceeding this value will be returned to the customer. Where an order is placed on an already discounted item where it clearly states that no discount code or voucher is to be used and the order is subsequently cancelled, an administration charge of £5.00 plus VAT may be applied.
Waiver
If you breach these conditions and we take no action, we will still be entitled to use our rights and remedies in any other situation where you breach these conditions.
Third Party Web Sites, Goods and Services
Masonic Collection Ltd may provide links to third party web sites that are not affiliated with Masonic Collection Ltd. We make no representations as to the quality, suitability, functionality or legality of any sites to which we may provide links or any goods or services available from such sites, and no such representations should be inferred or construed whether from such provision or otherwise.
All matters concerning any goods and services that you purchase from a third party site, including, without limitation all contract terms are solely between you and the owner of that site and Masonic Collection Ltd will not be liable for any costs or damages to you or any third party arising directly or indirectly out of any third party website.
Our contact details
Masonic Collection Ltd
18 Central Avenue
Coventry
CV2 4DP
United Kingdom
Tel: +44 (0) 24 7644 3469Continue
